Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother Tenzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the neighbors
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousand of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guilt that
take of his name in vain. Remember the
Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six days
shall thou labor and do all thy work,
but the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. In it thou shall not
do any work. thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it, honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
steal. Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
cover thy neighbor's house. Thou shall
not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors. We read Exodus 21-17.
And may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. Got brother
Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Jerome,
>> grace and peace.
>> Brother Tanzel.
>> Good evening.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Brother Sean.
>> Good evening.
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. What is our
first question of the program?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Uh
Charlotte says, "I was asked if a person
miss a Sabbath service and they are not
sick, they will be said they will be cut
off." So, they're not sure about joining
if this is true. Is this true?
>> All right. Well, first of all, we can't
say that because you missed a Sabbath
day, you're going to be cut off because
you were not sick. But let's go um
Tenzel, I want to read two places
because keep in mind, too, that the
Sabbath day is a holy day and it's a
special day and it should be delightful
for all who attend and it is honorable.
Let's go to Isaiah the 58th chapter and
let's read that 13 and 14.
Go ahead.
>> If thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath, from doing thy pleasure on my
holy day, and call the Sabbath a
delight, the holy of the Lord honorable,
and shall honor him, not doing thy own
ways, nor finding thy own pleasure, nor
speaking thy own words. Then sh thou
delighten thyself in the Lord, and I
will cause thee to ride upon the high
places of the earth, and feed thee with
the heritage of Jacob thy father, for
the mouth of the Lord have spoken. So
like I say, Lord say that his Sabbath
day is holy. It's a special day,
delightful, and we should delight oursel
in it because it's a blessing to have
the wisdom to know that you should be
there on the seventh day of the week,
which is Saturday. But let's go and read
Luke. Let's go Luke the 4th chapter.
Luke 4
cuz this was Jesus that was telling us
about this Sabbath day and how we should
keep it. But he also led by example. So
let's see what it says in Luke 4 and
pick it up at that verse 14.
Go ahead.
>> And Jesus returned in the power of the
spirit unto Galilee. And there went out
a fame of him throughout all the regions
round about.
>> And he taught in their synagogues being
glorified of all.
And he came to Nazareth where he had
been brought up. And his custom was he
went into the synagogue on the Sabbath
day and stood up for to read.
>> So there we go. Jesus led by example. He
went in the synagogue on the Sabbath day
and stood up for it to read. So, I see
what you're saying about joining. Is
this true? Hey, it would be of great
benefit to you to join because we teach
the pure uncut word of God. And we hope
that those answers straight out of the
book will bring some clarity to your
friend. And that's all I got.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next one. Danielle Willington wants to
know all the pagan holidays that
Christians should not celebrate.
>> All right. All these pagan holidays that
Christians should not celebrate. Brother
Julius,
>> uh you got your major days such as
Christmas. You got your uh other day,
the main two of the year is Easter. And
then you have your Valentine's Day. And
then you have your you don't celebrate
that and then you don't participate in
the Halloween festivals which is a
three-day festival. So you stay away
from those Christmas, Easter, Halloween,
Valentine's Day.
That's all I got.
>> All right, we hope that answered your
question as we keep on moving.
>> Yes, moving on. and MWMS
God's son asks in Amos 5 but they don't
give any scriptures
uh as contain to the does this contain
to the holidays like Easter Thanksgiving
Christmas and the other holidays
>> all right so Amos 5 is in question here
brother Julius
>> let's let's go to Amos 5il
Amos, go to Amos the 5th chapter
and let's look at what the Lord said.
Because when you read the whole chapter,
it is about uh the Lord's warning to
Israel and Israel's conduct. That's what
the whole chapter is about. Worshiping
the Lord in vain, what Israel did. And
the Lord is pleading with the people to
correct themselves and stay away from
these pagan gods. Let's pick it up at
the scripture that you're mentioning. Uh
uh pick it up at verse 20.
Go ahead when you get it. Amos 5 and 20.
Go ahead. Tail.
>> Shall not the day of the Lord be
darkness and not light, even very dark
and no brightness in it.
>> Go ahead.
>> I hate I despise your feast days. I will
not smell in your Sodom assemblies. So
your religious feast days and festivals
and what you do and your Sundays and and
and and the thing that you appertain to
the Lord which have nothing to do with
him. He said I hate that I despise your
feast days and I would not smell in your
solemn assemblies. Continue at verse 22.
>> Though you offer me burnt offerings and
your meat offerings, I will not accept
them.
>> Uhhuh. Neither will I regard the peace
offers of your fat beast.
>> Because you try to serve me, but in the
back of your mind, you serving them
other pag pagan gods. 23. Go ahead.
>> Take thou away from me the noise of thy
songs, but I will not hear the melody of
thy vows.
>> All the stuff that you appertain to me
has nothing to do with me. Now verse six
is what we want. Why? Why did the Lord
caution Israel about him about about the
thing that you do? Go ahead. Seek the
Lord, ye shall live.
>> Skip down to verse 26.
>> 26. But ye have borne the tabernacle of
your molec and shoot and shy your image.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The star of your God, which you made to
yourselves.
>> So now you adopted everybody else's
religion. Now you got the what you
believe to be the star of David, which
David never had a star. They had the ark
of the covenant and the Lord and the
priests go before them. Not this
so-called star of David, which is a
myth,
>> which is a myth and a pagan practice.
This is what the Lord say. Everything
that you have pertain to me, you got
that chain around your neck and all that
kind of stuff. You got the cross around
your neck. I ain't got nothing to do
with that, said the Lord. So, this is
what this scripture is actually talking
about, Cornell.
That's all I got.
you muted.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Matthew Frier asks, "Is
getting your teeth done or getting eye
bags removed a sin?" Uh, he's talking
about cosmetic surgery.
>> All right. So, what about uh your teeth
and your eye bags, Brother Dre?
>> Let's go to First John the 3 chapter and
read verse four.
No, it's not a sin.
This is what sin is. First John 3 and
four. Read it when you get it.
>> Whosoever committh sin, transgressive
also the law. For sin is the
transgression of the law.
>> And there's nowhere in the Bible that
says you can't get your teeth clean
or uh get a a bridge or or a uh your
bags removed from your eyes. That's all
I got.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, Dre. We know you don't
take care of them teeth. Sometime they
be in a glass on your nightstand. That's
right. [laughter]
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
>> moving on. Linda Stringer says Paul says
in 1 Corinthians 4:E7
that men who pray with their heads
covered dishonor their head God. But in
Exodus 28:4
required the priest to cover their heads
with a miter or turban. Is this a
contradiction?
>> All right. Heads covered versus
uncovered, brother Jerome.
>> Well, let's go read those verses that
you gave.
>> 1 Corinthians 4 and 7.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> For who maketh thee to defer from
another? And why is thou that thou
didest not receive?
Nor if thou didest receive it, why dost
thou glory as if thou has not received
it?
>> Okay. I don't think that's the verse you
really wanted.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think it's in the 11th chapter
of first Corinthians.
>> Yeah.
>> Verse that you want.
>> Um.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's more fitting,
brother. Right.
>> Verse 11, verse 4. Chapter 11, verse 4.
>> Oh, okay. Every man praying or
prophesying, having his head cover,
dishonor of his head.
>> Okay. I think that's the one you want.
Now, the other one you gave was Exodus
28 and4.
Read
that.
>> And these are the garments which thou
shalt make a breastplate and a ephod and
a robe and a broader coat and maid
and a girdle. And they shall make holy
garments for Aaron thy brother and his
son that he lay minister unto me in the
priest's office.
Okay. Now, it's not a contradiction
uh because
uh there's things the Lord gave uh the
litical priests of the sons of Aaron,
>> he gave them a job to do. There's a
service in the temple. Okay? And in the
inner court and when they were doing
that service, the Lord had them to wear
holy garments.
Okay? the high priest, he will have a a
a mitra and a crown on when he doing his
service. And
the uh the uh sons of Aaron, the priest,
they would uh wear bonnets when they
would do their service uh in the temple
in in a court. All right? But when they
came, they wasn't supposed to leave them
on. Uh they were supposed to take them
off when they got through with their
service and they were supposed to leave
the temple under the court uh uh in a
court. They were supposed to take all
them garments off including their head
wear. They supposed to take them off.
Okay. So let's go um let's go to Ezekiel
chapter 44
and we're going to read verse 15-19.
Ezekiel chapter 44. Yeah. Verse 15
through 19.
>> Okay.
But the priest, the Levite, the son of
Zadok, that kept the child in my
sanctuary, when the children of Israel
went astray from me, they shall come
near to me to minister unto me, and they
shall stand before me, to offer unto me
the fat and the blood, said the Lord
God. They shall enter into into my
sanctuary, and they shall come near to
my table to minister unto me, and they
shall keep my charge. And it shall come
to pass that when they enter in at the
gate of the inner court, they should be
clothed with linen garments, and no war
shall come upon them while they minister
in the gates of the inner court and
within. They shall have linen bonnets
upon their heads, and shall have linen
breaches upon their loins. They shall
not g themselves with anything that
causes sweat. Mhm.
>> And when they go forth into the upper
the utter court, even into the utter
court of the people, they shall put off
their garments, wherein they minister,
and lay them in the holy chambers, and
they shall put on other garments, and
they should not sanctify the people with
their garments,
>> their garments, that including the head
wear. Okay? So, um they had to do like
the regular people as far as uh praying.
Their head has to be uncovered. But when
they doing the service in the temple,
the Lord required them to wear head gear
for that service. Okay. So that's all I
got on it.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question. As we
move on,
>> moving on. The K family says, "The
lesson about the law was really good.
The only thing I didn't really
understand was Jesus making the animal
sacrifice, but he said it was impossible
for animal blood to take away sin.
Please explain.
>> All right, we're glad that you enjoyed
that lesson. Um, and we're going to now
ask the guest caller to shed some light.
Okay, first thing is
the uh law of animal sacrifice
was a school master to bring us to
Christ.
>> Let's go and read that. Galatians the 3
chapter and read verse 24.
Wherefore the law was our school master
to bring us unto Christ that we might be
justified by faith.
>> Read the next one.
>> But after that faith has come, we are no
longer under a school master.
>> So now, what's a school master? He's
somebody that teaches you. Isn't that
correct?
>> Yep. And and what did uh uh what did
this law as a school master teach you?
Let's go into Romans the 6th chapter and
verse 23.
Read it when you get there.
>> For the wages of sin is death, but the
gift of God is eternal life through
Jesus Christ our Lord.
Now that's what that school m that law
was to teach you that the wages of sin
is death. So the Lord added it so it
would show you not to commit sin because
man is dying right now because Adam and
Eve sin in the garden. So you can't get
away from the first death. But the whole
thing is if you continue to sin, you
going to die the second death which is
the lake of fire and eternal. So he
added animal sacrifice
as a school as a teacher because of a
school master to teach you
stop sinning cuz if you don't you are
going to die the second death. M.
>> So that's why it never was designed.
It never was designed to uh uh uh uh uh
deliver uh remove your sins. It was
designed to stop you from sinning. And
the only blood that could remove your
sin was the blood of Jesus. That's why
Jesus had to die.
So the reason he gave us animal
sacrifice is to show us that the wage of
sin is death. When you sin against God,
somebody or something have to die.
And you can't avoid the first death. But
if you continue to sin, you going to die
the second death. That is the lesson
that we get from the law of animal
sacrifice.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. We hope that answered your
question there as we continue to move
on.
>> Moving on. Eta Masala says, "Apart from
1 Corinthians 6 verse 19, are there
scriptures that one can use against
plastic surgeries, animal to human
transplants or genetic in engineering?"
>> All right. just call apart from 1
Corinthians 6 and19 what about all these
other things plastic surgery etc.
Yeah. Let's see what first Corinthians
say 9 and 6 and 19.
>> Okay. What know ye not that your body is
the temple of the Holy Ghost which is in
you which ye have of God and ye are not
your own?
>> So now that was referring to when a guy
go out and sleep with a harlot.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
someone with the holler, but that have
nothing to do uh uh uh with the uh face
lifts. Uh uh what else they call it?
>> Plastic surgeries.
>> Plastic surgery.
That is not sin.
Sin was read to you once. Uh sin was
read what sin was was read once already.
But read it again. Go to first John.
Read verses chapter 3 and verse 4.
>> Right? Whosoever committh sin,
transgressive also the law. For sin is
the transgression of the law.
>> That's what sin is.
Not
faceelift.
And that first Corinthian you just read
earlier, that was talking about John and
yourself going out and committing
fornication with prostitutes.
That's sin because you're committing
fornication.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. We hope that answers your
question as we move to our next one.
>> Next one. Brick Brat asks, "Is
Revelations 22 verse 19 and Matthew 5
verse 19 good scriptures to share with
people that the Old Testament still
stands. They think the Old Testament
doesn't matter. All you have to do is
love." I told them Jesus was crucified
to terminate the animal sacrifice.
Brother Dre, we know that both books
together are required. What you say,
brother?
>> That the scriptures say to the law and
to the testimony, if you don't speak
according to this word is because there
is no light in you.
>> That's right.
>> But let's go over to uh Revelation the
22nd chapter and we going to read uh
verses 14 and 15. Then we'll skip to
that 19. Go ahead when you get it.
Tanzel,
>> blessed are they that do his
commandments, that they may have right
to the tree of life,
>> and may enter in through the gates into
the city. For for without our dogs and
sorcerers, and whoreongers, and
murderers, and idoltors, and whosoever
loveth, and maketh a lie.
>> So these commandments matter.
You know, the only law that's done away
with is that law of animal sacrifices
and those things that came along with
that fringes and some other things cuz
he said, "I'mma put my laws in your
inward part and write them in your
heart."
>> That's right.
>> Now, let's go over to Matthew 5. Matthew
five. And we gonna read that verse 19
that they got Matthew 5 and 19.
Go ahead, brother.
>> Whosoever therefore shall break one of
these least commandments, and shall
teach men so, he shall be called the
least in the kingdom of heaven. But
whosoever shall do and teach them the
same shall be called great in the
kingdom of heaven.
>> Yes, sir. So, that's good. But, you
know, the other thing that they said is
they think that the Old Testament
doesn't matter. All you have to do is
love. So, let's look at that. Let's look
at something in the New Testament about
how you love. Let's go to uh Romans 13.
Romans 13 and we're going to pick it up
at verse 8 and we're going to read from
8 to 10. Romans 13 8-10. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Owe no man anything but to love one
another. For he that loveth another hath
fulfilled the law. For this thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
kill. Thou shalt not steal. Thou shall
not bear false witness. Thou shall not
coveret. And if there be any other
commandment, it is briefly comprehended
in this saying, namely,
thou shall love thy neighbor as thyself.
Does love workketh no ill to his
neighbor. Therefore, love is the
fulfilling of the law.
>> So, if you keeping the commandments,
you are fulfilling the law of love. You
are loving. And that's what love is. And
Jesus said in John 14:15, "If you love
me, keep my commandments." He didn't
say, "I'mma nail them to the cross." One
last thing they mention here is uh is
that
animal
you that they told Jesus was sacrificed
to terminate animal sacrifices.
Well, the guest caller just read that.
But let's go look at that one more time
in Galatians 3 and we going to read
verse 19
and see that this was added because they
broke the commandments of God. This law
of animal sacrifices. Go ahead and read
it, brother. Wherefore then served the
law, it was added because of
transgression, till the seed should come
to whom the promise was made. It was
ordained by angels in the hand of a
mediator.
>> And that seed that was to come, that was
promised to Abraham, that in Abraham's
seed shall all nations of the earth be
blessed.
>> That seed is Christ.
>> Now, I want you to read verse 25, and
that'll be it. Go ahead.
But after that faith is come, we are no
longer under a school master.
>> That's right. So that faith which is
Christ, when he comes, we are no longer
under that school master, which is
animal sacrifice, not the commandments.
That's all I got.
>> Hey, brother Dre, can we read one verse
out of that Deuteronomy 4?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Because they were saying the Old
Testament don't matter. But well, we
getting ready to read back up what you
read early in that Revelation 22 and 19,
that verse two, Tanzel, Deuteronomy 4
and two.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You shall not add unto the word which I
command you, neither shall ye dim the
art from it, that ye may keep the
commandments of the Lord your God, which
I command you."
>> Excellent, brother.
>> Yeah. Praise the Lord. Because if uh
that right there tell us we got to keep
that old testament to don't it
>> law and the testimony.
>> Yep. Or you diminishing from it. So
>> yes sir.
>> Thank you for that brother. Hope they
receive that light as we move on to our
next question.
>> Next one. Dborah Walder wants
explanation on Ezekiel 14
12-4
and 17- 20.
All right, Ezekiel 14. Let's go there,
Tanzel.
Let's pick it up at that verse 12. And
then the next one to be Ezekiel 14 17-
20 with some light shed on it. Go right
ahead, brother. And the guest caller
will take it from there. Ezekiel
14:12-14.
>> Okay. The word of the Lord came again to
me, saying, "Son of man, when the land
sinnth against me by trespassing
grievously, then will I stretch out my
hand upon it, will break the staff of
the bread thereof, and will send famine
upon it, and will cut off man and beast
from it. Though these three men, Noah,
Daniel, and Job, were in it, they should
deliver but their own souls by their
righteousness, said the Lord God.
Read 17-20.
>> Or if I bring a sword upon the land and
say, "Sord, go to the land so that I cut
off man and beast from it. Though these
three men were in it, as I live, sayeth
the Lord God, they shall deliver neither
son nor daughter, but they only shall be
delivered themselves. If I said a
pestilent
or if I said a pest,
>> what verse is that?
>> That was in 18.
>> Read the 20.
Or if I send a pestilent into that land
and pour out my fury upon it in blood,
to cut off from it man, and beast,
though Noah, Daniel, and Job were in it,
as I live, said the Lord God, they
should deliver neither son nor daughter,
they should but deliver them their own
souls by their righteousness.
>> Only thing that's simply saying is that
can't nobody save you but you.
>> That's right. can't save
and your friends can't save you. Your
spouses can't save you. You can only
save yourself by your own righteousness.
>> It's just like nobody can get you cut
off.
You can get yourself cut off by your own
unrighteousness.
Other words, you're responsible for
yourself. Let's go to Ezekiel the 18th
chapter
and we going to read verse 4 first.
Behold,
all souls are mine. As the soul of the
father, so also the soul of the son is
mine. The soul that sinnth, it shall
die.
>> And that and that is what the Lord is
letting you know. the soul that sent it,
it shall die, you know, and and can't
nobody else get you cut off. But back
back up to verse one, and we're going to
read down to it cuz I cuz it used to be
when when when somebody did something
when the father did something or the the
children suffered. Verse one, read it.
The word of the Lord came unto me again,
saying, What mean ye that ye use this
proverb concerning the land of Israel,
saying, The fathers have eaten sour
grapes, and the children teeth are set
on edge? As I live, sayeth the Lord God,
ye shall not have occasion anymore to
use this proverb in Israel. Behold,
>> that's what it that's what it used to
be. Father committed a sin, his children
suffered for everybody in his household.
He said, "But it ain't going to be no."
>> He read, "Behold, all souls are mine. As
the soul of the father, so also the soul
of the son is mine. The soul that
sinnth, it shall die."
>> Now skip down to verse 20 and read 20
and 21.
>> The soul that sinnth, it shall die. The
son shall not bear the iniquity of the
fathers, neither shall the father bear
the iniquity of the son. The
righteousness of the righteous
shall be upon him. The wickedness of the
wicked shall be upon him.
>> So if the Lord bring drama on the land,
only the righteous can save themselves.
>> They can't save nobody else. And vice
versa.
If you uh uh uh uh if somebody in your
family sin your father, they cannot get
you cut off. They will get off only get
themselves cut off by their own
unrighteousness like you can only save
yourself by your own righteousness.
That's what it's saying. But every soul
is responsible for his own salvation.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, sir. That is a fair program there,
sir.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question with a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:05. Valencia wants to
know
is Okay, who Valencia wants to know who
is the first martyr? Was this Stefan or
James John's brother?
>> All right, brother Jerome, the first
martyr.
where [clears throat] you you can read
where um Stefan uh was martyed and um
possibly um James
uh John's brother was martyed, but I
wouldn't consider them the first to be
martyed. Let's let's look at the uh
definition of martyr. Um if you will,
let's let me see if I can find it right
quick. It says a person who is killed or
made to suffer because of their
religious um beliefs. And in this case,
we talking about belief in the true and
living God and being a servant to the
true and living God. Okay? Uh so no,
Stephan wouldn't be the first that was
martyed for that. Abel would be the
first that was martyed for that when he
was killed by his brother Cain. Okay.
So, uh cuz he did that which was right
in the eyes of God and his brother was
jealous because of it and he slew him
because of that. Yeah. So, uh
a verse I wanted to give was Matthews
23.
Can you read Matthews 23 verse 34 and
35?
23. 34 and 35.
>> Yeah.
But behold, I say unto you prophets,
wise men, and scribes, and some of them
ye shall killed and crucified, and some
of them shall be scourged in your
synagogues, and persecuted them from
city to city,
that upon you may come all the righteous
blood shed upon the earth, from the
blood of righteous Abel unto the blood
of Zachariah, the son of Baracas.
>> Yeah.
between the temple and the altar.
>> Yeah. I just want to tie that with First
John chapter 3
verse 11 through13.
>> First John 3.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> For this is the message that you heard
from the beginning that we should love
one another. Now that's Cain, who was of
that wicked one, and slew his brother,
and wherefore slew he him, because his
own works were evil, and his brothers
righteous. But marvel not, my brethren,
if the world hate you.
>> Yeah, that's all I got on it.
>> All right, thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on,
>> moving on. Charles Tumer asks, "If a
wife or husband cheated once,
could they be forgiven and be saved if
they are sorry and don't do it again?"
>> Brother Julius,
>> absolutely.
If they are sorry and repent and and
walk in righteousness, sure they can be
be forgiven. Let's go to a couple of
places and let's give you an example of
that. Let's go to Matthew.
Matthew the 12th chapter. I got one
verse there, Tanzel.
Look what the Lord said. See, the Lord
don't judge like we judge.
>> Matthew 12 and 31.
Here's your answer. One of them. Go
ahead, brother. Wherefore I say unto
you, all manner of sin and blasphemy
shall be forgiven unto men, but the
blasphemy against the Holy Ghost shall
not be forgiven unto men.
>> So all manner of sin shall be forgiven.
Okay? So you acknowledge your
transgression, your sin, and you uh uh
pray to the Lord and
uh uh ask the person to uh your spouse
to forgive you.
and you walk in righteousness. Yeah, you
could be forgiven. Let's go to a a
perfect example. 1 Corinthians the 6th
chapter.
1 Corinthians chapter 6 tanzel. We're
going to read 9 to11. 1 Corinthians 6
9-11.
And let's pay attention to what we
reading. Okay? 1 Corinthians 6 9-11.
When you get it, brother, go ahead and
read it. Know ye not that the
unrighteous shall not inherit the
kingdom of God?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Be not deceived. Neither fornicators.
>> Fornicators.
>> No idoltors.
No adulterers.
>> Oh, you cheated. No adulterers. Go
ahead.
>> Nor epheminate.
No abusers of themselves.
>> Come on, Tenzel.
>> But mankind.
>> Go ahead. nor thieves, nor covetous, nor
drunker, nor revilers, nor extortioners
shall inherit the kingdom of God. Now
give me verse 11. Look what the Lord
said through the mouth of all. Go ahead.
>> And such were some of you,
>> and such were some of you, cuz all have
sinned and come short of the glory of
God. But God is merciful, and he want us
to acknowledge those sins and go and sin
no more. and such were some of you. But
now you repented like the guest caller
said in Ezekiel the 18th chapter. You
acknowledge your transgress and you
sorry and you want to walk in
righteousness. Such were some of you.
But what now t
>> but ye are washed.
>> Yes.
>> But you are sanctified.
>> You are justified in the name of the
Lord Jesus.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And by the spirit of our God.
>> That's why he came to save men from
their sins.
That's why you sin against God. You try
not to do it willingly and then you
repent and you go like he told a woman
they called in adultery. Go and sin no
more. That's all I got.
>> Yes, sir. All right. Hope that answers
your question. We moving on.
>> Moving on. Linda Stringer asks, "Were
the Horites who dwell in Mount Seir
married into Esau and were they people
with leprosy? I understand they were
different from other humans."
>> All right, got a little bit tied into
that question, but guest caller, please.
Well, I didn't uh uh I I really didn't
uh uh read that. That wasn't on the list
for me to look at. And I and uh uh we
can go and I don't know where is
mentioned about the whole whole rights.
I know uh Esau children uh
you know they they tell you who came out
of Esau. Now if somebody can grab a
scripture, we can go read it and see who
came out of Esau.
All right, we can go to that. Uh, I
guess Genesis 14 and 6 would be a a good
start for one. Then there's a few other
places, but Genesis 14
and six,
>> Genesis 36:21
and 29 explains that that's talking
about Edom, the Dukes of Esau.
>> Oh, okay. Hey, well, let's go there
because mine was just saying um that
they were in Mount Seir,
>> but uh let's go to where you said,
Genesis 36.
>> Yeah, go to six and pick it up at verse
19.
>> 36 and 19.
>> Yeah, read down to 21.
>> These are the sons of Esau, who is Edom,
and these are their dukes. These are the
s sons of Sea the Horite who inhabit the
land and Shabbal and Zibian and Ani
and Dishon and Ezar and Dishon. These
are the dukes of the Horites, the
children of Seir in the land of Edom.
>> So these these were descendants of Edom,
Esau.
And then blank.
>> Yeah. Now read that. Read that. Gen
read. You got to read that. Genesis 10
and 25.
>> Genesis 10 and 25.
>> Yeah, you got to read that.
And unto Ebra were born two sons. The
name of one was Pelag, for in his days
was the earth divided, and his brother
name was Jotton.
>> Yeah, did I say Genesis 10 and 25? I'm
sorry. I meant the I meant the I'm
sorry. Forgive me. I meant uh the
Genesis 14 where it was talking about
the Horites during the times of uh
Abraham.
>> Yes.
>> When he was fighting those kings. Yeah.
When he was fighting those kings
>> when they took when they took Lot.
Okay. Yeah. Well, you pick it up at that
verse six and then we'll go where from
there.
>> Yeah. It's in uh Genesis 14 verse 6.
>> And the Horites in their mount Seir unto
El Pan which is by the wilderness. And
they returned to Cain to Emispat which
is Kadesh and smoke all the country of
the Malachites. and also the Amorites
that dwell in Hazatimar.
And there went out of the king of Sodom
and the king of Gomorrah and the king of
Admma and the king of Zaboam and the
king of Bilah. And the same of is Zora.
And they joined battle with them in the
vow of Sidum,
with Shadlemore, the king of Elam, and
with Tidal, king of nations, and Am
Amberfell, king of Shinar, and Arich,
king of Eleazar,
Elisar, four kings with five.
Keep going.
>> Yeah. In verse 12, it said they took
Lot, Abraham's. Yeah. And they took Lock
Abraham's brother's son dwelt in Sodom
and his goods and departed.
>> Yeah.
>> So all through all of those people that
that name he come out of Esau, it wasn't
white folks.
>> They didn't marry in they didn't marry
into Edom. They they descended of Edom.
>> Huh?
>> They're descendants of Edom. They didn't
marry into Esau.
>> Right. And he talking about the white
people. Edom look like white people but
he's not
>> right.
>> He's fell but he is not out of the same
lineage.
So Edom uh uh
Hebrews believe he or not and they are
seemetic.
It's like the Arabs are Hebrews and
they're Seemetic.
Like we are Hebrews and we're Seemetic,
but we're different color from them to
know. All right. Then Mary and Edom need
come out of the lineage of Edom.
>> That's all.
>> Yeah. And
>> go ahead, Deborah. Because they're
asking about leprosy, too,
>> right? They want to know and were they
people with leprosy? It doesn't say that
from the scriptures you read. And uh and
are they different from other humans?
>> No, [snorts] they're not.
Look at soal you. You look at a whole
>> And Genesis 25 say that it's two nations
were in their womb and two of people.
That's what it says.
Yeah, but they come out of they didn't
they they came out of Isaac
seed. So,
>> right. Right. Esau was red and hairy
when he came out.
>> Right.
>> Two nations wound was Esau and us.
>> Exactly.
>> That's right.
>> Yep.
>> You know, so the whole come out of Esau.
>> Yes. and the other nation
in the wound with Esau was us. That's
our sin prince twin brother even though
we're different colors.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
All right.
Which is also known as Jacob. All right.
We hope that answered your question as
we move on to our next one.
>> Moving on. King Likable wants you to
explain Genesis 10 verse 25.
Uh, was that passage referring to
earthquakes
and did that ever happened in the Bible?
>> Genesis 10 and 25. Jerome, go right
ahead. [clears throat]
>> Um, let's go read it.
>> Genesis 10:25.
>> Yeah. Yep.
>> I just read this, didn't I? [laughter]
>> Yeah, that was my mistake. I'm sorry.
>> No, I'm just
And to Ebra were born two sons, and the
name of one was Pag, for in his days was
the earth divided, and his brother name
was Joan.
>> Yeah. So no, it it's actually referring
to uh the time when the Lord had
confounded the languages, you know, so
that the people would divide and scatter
>> cuz the Lord want the whole earth
populated, you know, but they wanted to
congregate and stay in one area and they
built that tower. So that's what the
divide is talking about. This talking
about the Lord dividing the people when
he sc when he confounded their languages
so he can scatter them so that the whole
earth can be covered with with the
people.
>> All right. So um
>> can you read Genesis 11 verse 1-8
and the whole earth was of one language
and of one speech. And it came to pass
as they journeyed from the east that
they found a plain land of Shannar and
they dwelt there. They said one to
another, "Go to and let us make bricks
and burn them thoroughly." And they had
brick for stone, and slime the head for
mortar. And they said, "Go to let us
build us a city and a tower whose top
may reach unto heaven, and let us make
us a name, lest we be scattered abroad
upon the face of the whole earth."
>> But that's what the Lord wanted.
You know, but they they said, "No, we
don't want to be scattered." Keep
reading.
The Lord came down to see the city and
the tower was the children of men built.
The Lord said, "Behold, the people is
one, and they have all one language, and
this they begin to do, and now nothing
will be restrained from them which they
have imagined to do."
Go to let us go down, and there confound
their language, that they may not
understand one another's speech." So the
Lord scattered them abroad from this
upon the face of all the earth. They
left off to build the city.
>> Yeah.
>> Therefore is the name of it called Babel
because the Lord did there confound the
language of all the earth. And from this
did the Lord scatter them abroad upon
the face of all the earth.
>> Yeah. Verse 25 in that 10th chapter was
talking about in the days of Paleleg
that took place
>> when they divided and and was scattered.
That's all I got.
>> Yeah. So that earth divided was not an
earthquake. It's just the people were
>> scattered, brother.
>> Scattered. Yeah.
>> Yes sir. Thank you for that. Hope that
answer question as we move on to our
next.
>> Moving on. Paul Israel bound asks the
things that are happening to Gaza now.
Is that because of prophecy? Are these
scriptures future or did they happen to
Gaza already? And the scriptures given
are Amos 1 6-8
and Jeremiah 47
verses 1-7.
>> All right, Tenzel, let's go to that.
Amos 1, you got Hosea, Joel, then Amos.
Amos 1 6-8. They want to know if this
was past or is it future coming with
Gaza? And the guest caller will share
some light from there. Amos 1 verse 6-8.
>> Thus sayeth the Lord, for these
transgression of Gaza, and for fourth, I
will not turn away the punishment
thereof, because they carried away cat
of the whole captivity to deliver them
up to Edom. But I will send a fire on
the wall of Gaza, which shall devour the
palaces thereof. Now when I cut off the
inhabitants from Ashdod, and him that
beholdeth scepter from Ashcolon,
and I will turn my hand from Echron, and
the remnant of the Philistines shall
perish, said the Lord God.
>> Uh verse 10,
>> thus say the Lord,
>> so as Amos one
verses 6-8
and then Jeremiah 47:es
1-7.
>> Right. That's what you want to read.
What did you just read?
>> I read Amos 6-8.
>> Okay. Go to uh Jeremiah 47 1-7.
>> Jeremiah 47.
>> Yes. Was it? Mhm.
>> Pick it up at verse one. Jeremiah 47
and1. Read down to seven.
>> The word of the Lord came to Jeremiah
the prophet against the Philistines
before that Pharaoh smoke Gassa. Thus
sayeth the Lord, behold, waters rise up
out of the north, and shall be an
overflowing flood, and shall overflow
the land, and all that is therein the
city, and them that dwell therein. Then
the men shall cry, and all the
inhabiters of the land shall howl at the
noise of the stamping of the hoofs of
the strong horses, at the rushing of his
chariots, and at the rumbling of his
wheels. The father shall not look back
to their children. for a feebleness of
hands, because of the day that cometh to
spoil all the Philistines, to cut off
from Tyrus and Sidon every helper that
remainth. For the Lord will spoil the
Philistine, the remnant of the country
of capture. Baldness has come upon Gaza.
Ascalon is cut off with the remnant of
their valleys. How long will thou cut
thyself? Oh, thou sword of the Lord, how
long will it be? Thou be quiet, put up
thyself into thy scabbard, rest, be
still.
How can he be quiet, seeing the Lord has
given it a charge against Escalon and
against the seashore? There have he
appointed it.
Okay,
that prophecy has been fulfilled
because the people that's in the land
now are Arabs and Arabs come out of
Ishmael. Let's go into Genesis the 16th
chapter
and we're going to start reading at the
we're going to read from one uh let's
see
1 to 4 then we're going to skip
>> Genesis 16 1-4.
>> Mhm. Now Sarah, Abraham's wife, bear him
no children, and she had an handmade, an
Egyptian, whose name was Hagar. And
Sarah said unto Abram, "Behold now, the
Lord hath restrained me from bearing. I
pray thee, go in unto my maid, and it
may be that I may obtain children by
her." And Abraham heard to the voice of
Sarah.
And Sarah, Abram<unk>s wife, took Hagar,
her maid, the Egyptians. after Abraham
had dwelt 10 years in the land of
Canaan, and gave her to her husband
Abraham's to be his wife. And he went in
unto Hagar, and she conceived. And when
she saw that she had conceived, her
mistress was despised in her eyes.
>> Okay, so now Abraham had this son by the
Egyptian woman. And let's see what he
named him. Skip down to verse 15 and
read it.
And Hagar bare Abraham a son. And
Abraham called his son's name which
Hagar bear Ishmael.
>> Okay. So now Ishmael, he is the father
of the Arabs. That those are the ones
that's uh uh uh that's dealing right now
in the land over there. So that let me
know that this been fulfilled cuz the
Arabians right now are the ones that's
over there because the gods of the
Philistines was Hites,
>> right?
>> Israel is a Shemite. And I'm going show
you what I mean by the Hammites. Let's
go into Genesis the 10th chapter.
Genesis chapter 10, we're going to read
six and then we're going to skip down
and read uh uh 13 and 14.
And the sons of Ham, Kush and Misrael,
and foot in Canaan.
>> Now skip down to verse 13. Read 13 and
14.
and Misra be at Ludum and Anm and Laab
and Nept and and Neptune
and and Path Museum and Cathm out of
whom came the Philist
which are the Philistine Gather black
folks amites but the Arabs over there
are Seemetic
they are sheites They come out of
Abraham. So,
>> yep.
>> And the tri and the uh uh uh uh the
Philistines was a part of the tribes of
Cana of of of nations of Canaan, the
sons of Canaan. So now, Israel drove
them out and got their land and then the
Arabs drove out the Philistines, what
was left of them, and now they're over
there in the land. So, this is not them.
This prophecy has already been
fulfilled.
All right,
good question. Good light. Let us keep
moving on to our next one.
>> Next one. Read the Bible daily asked in
Luke 22:32.
What did Jesus mean
when he said, "When thou are converted,
straighten thy brethren?" When thou art
converted, then go and strengthen thy
brother, brother Dre. What that mean?
>> Let's go to Luke uh 22. You asked about
32, but we going to bag up and read
verse 31.
>> Start at 31, read 31 and 32, brother. Go
ahead when you get it.
And the Lord said, Simon, Simon, behold,
Satan have desired to have you, that he
may sift you as wheat, but I have prayed
for thee that thy faith fail not, and
without I converted, strengthen thy
brother.
>> So he, you know, Jesus is letting
uh Peter know what's happening that that
Satan wants to sift him like wheat. And
uh he said he prayed for him
that his faith don't fail because he
going to be tried here. And he said when
you are converted strengthen your
brother. But read 33 and 34. Go ahead.
>> And he said unto him, Lord, I am ready
to go with thee both into prison and to
death. Mhm.
>> He said, "I tell thee, Peter, the
shall not crow this day, before that
thou shalt thrice deny that thou knowest
me."
>> So Jesus told Peter, he said, "Look, you
going to deny me three times
before the
crow." But let's go and look at
something there. Let's go to Matthew 26
real quick. Matthew 26. We not going to
look at all of it. We going to look at
what what what uh how Peter felt after
all this was done.
Matthew 26 and just read verse 75. Go
ahead.
And Peter remember the word of Jesus
which said unto him before the cockcrow,
thou shalt deny me thrice. And he went
out and wept bitterly. because he denied
him three times. And if you read from
verse 69 all the way down to 75, it will
tell you that. And so he said, "After
you are converted, strengthen your
brother." He let them know what was
going to happen. He said, "After you
converted, strengthen your brother." So
that's exactly what Peter did. and he
went about to not only
uh after he was converted, he went to
convert others. Let's look at that.
Let's go to Acts the 3 chapter.
Acts the third chapter and we just going
to read verses 19 and 20. Acts 3 19 and
20. Go ahead when you get it, brother.
This is Peter talking here.
Go ahead. Repent ye therefore and be
converted that your sins may be blotted
out for the time of refreshing shall
come from the presence of the Lord and
he shall send Jesus Christ which before
was preached unto you.
>> So the Lord prayed for uh Peter that
that his faith don't fail him and
Peter's faith
stood and he went about telling them to
repent. the chapter before that,
>> he was dealing with them
>> and telling them on the day of Pentecost
what they did to Jesus. And they said,
"Men and brethren, what shall we do?"
And Peter said, "Repent every one of
you, and be baptized in the name of
Jesus, and 3,000 souls were added." But
here in 19, he said, "Repent ye
therefore, and be converted." Same thing
Jesus said, when you are converted,
strengthen your brother. So that's what
that's about. That's all I got.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I like it. Throw one that's a little
simpler. Better you stop saying it, then
go out and teach your brothers to stop
saying it.
>> That's it.
>> That's it. Well said. Yes, sir.
>> Y All right. That is the job of every
man walking in the trueness of God. All
right, hope that answered your question
there as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Paul, Israelbound asks, "What
does it mean that God will inherit all
nations?" And Psalms 82:8
is given.
>> Psalms 82 and verse 8. And we're gonna
open this up to the panel, too. What
does it mean about God will inherit all
nations?
>> Go right ahead, brother.
>> Arise, oh God, judge the earth, but thou
shalt inherit all nations.
>> Okay, let's go. It said inherit all
nation. This
>> contradicts all of the Sunday
preachers teaching about going to
heaven.
Let's show you what he mean. Let's start
in Psalm chapter 2 1-8. We're going to
read quick because I got a lot quite a
few. I want to do this by read reason
I'm doing it because I want people to
know how is it that you going to teach
to somebody that's going to go to heaven
and all over the book that you know that
the Lord Jesus going to run this earth
before the father come down to it.
Psalms 2 1-8. He said Psalms 2 chapter.
>> Yeah. Yep.
All right.
>> Read it.
>> Why do the heathen rage and the people
imagine a vain thing? The kings of the
earth set themselves and the rulers take
counsel together against the Lord and
against his anointed saying. Let us
break their bands of sunder, cast away
their cords from us. But he that siteth
in the heaven shall laugh. The Lord
shall have them in derision. Then shall
he speak unto them in his wrath, and vex
them in his sword displeasure. Yet have
I set my kings upon my holy hill of
Zion. I will declare the decree. The
Lord hath said unto me, Thou art my son.
This day have I begotten thee. But ask
of me and I shall give thee the heathen
for an inheritance and the uttermost
parts of the earth for thy possession.
Okay. So he say going to give him the
heathen which is the nations for his
inheritance and the uttermost part of
the earth for his possession. That's
what that's he going to inherit the
nation. But go to make and let's look at
it. Let's let's go to Matthews 21 read
verse 1-5.
Matthews 21
1-5.
And when they drew n to Jerusalem, they
were come to Beth Page unto mouth to the
mount of olives. Then sent Jesus two
disciples, saying unto them, Go into the
village over against you. And
straightway ye shall find an ass tied in
a coat with her, Loose them, and bring
them unto me. And if any man say ought
unto you, ye shall say, The Lord have
need of them, and straightway he will
send them. All this was done that it
might be fulfilled, which was spoken by
the prophet, saying, Tell ye the
daughter of Zion, king, behold, the king
cometh unto thee, me, and sitting upon
an ass, and a coat, the f of an ass.
He as he said, "Now I want you to tell
the daughters of Zion." It's the
fulfilled prophecy that said, "Tell the
daughters of Zion, thy king coming unto
you riding on an ass quote the fold of
an ass." Well, let's look at that
prophecy where uh uh uh Jesus just
quoted. Let's go into Zechariah 9 and
we're going to read verses 9 and 10.
>> Rejoice greatly, oh daughter of Zion.
Shout, O daughter of Jerusalem. Behold,
thy king cometh unto thee. He is just,
and having salvation, lowly, and riding
upon an ass, and upon a coat the fo of
an ass. And I will cut off this.
>> Go ahead.
>> And I will cut off the chariot from
Ephraim, and the horse from Jerusalem,
and the Bible shall be cut off. He shall
speak peace unto the heathens and his
dominion shall be from sea even to sea
and from the rivers even to the ends of
the earth.
>> That let you know now he going his
dominion going to be from sea to sea
from the river even to the end of the
earth. In other words, Jesus going to
rule this end [clears throat]
time
right then.
>> He told you that in Revelation the 12th
chapter. So go to Revelation 12 and read
1, 2, and skip down to five.
And there and there appeared a great one
in heaven, a woman clothed with the sun
and the moon under her feet, and upon
her head a crown of 12 stars,
and she being with child crying and
birth, and pain to be delivered.
Verse five.
>> And she brought forth a manchild who was
to rule all nation with a rod of iron.
And her child was caught up under God
into his throne.
>> So that manchild that's to rule all
nation with the rod of iron is Jesus. So
he going back. He's sitting on the
throne at the right hand of the father
now. But he's going to come back. Last
place Zechariah 14. We're going to read
verses 1
3 uh 1 3 4 and nine.
Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, and
thy spoil shall be divided in the midst
of thee.
Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations as when he fought
in the day of battle.
And ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountains, for the valley of the
mountain shall reach unto Ael. Yeah, ye
shall flee like as he fled from before
the earthquake in the days of Uzziah,
king of Judah. And the Lord my God shall
come and all the saints with thee.
>> Skip now to verse n and read it.
>> And the Lord shall be king over all the
earth. That day shall there be one Lord
and his name one.
Mhm.
>> So that's what it mean then. What is he
going to give you uh uh uh uh the
heathen of the nations for your
inheritance? He just simply saying that
Jesus is going to rule this whole earth
for a thousand years.
>> And once a thousand years is over with
and white Germans been made by Jesus
then the father is going to come down to
the earth. But it see but
but as it is now Jesus gonna inherit the
earth. He gonna run the earth. He is not
gonna steal you off the heaven.
>> That's all it's saying that Jesus going
to come and rule this earth.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> That's right. Lord told us he created
the earth to be inhabited.
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
As we go into new territory. Correct
Deborah? Uh yes, we are in new
territory. We are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, January the 14, 2026.
>> Kylie Parker asks, "Is it a sin?" We got
these sin questions again. Is it a sin
to be glutton? Someone who eats a lot or
over eats. What does this scripture
mean? in Proverb 23
20 and 21.
>> Proverbs 23
>> Yes.
>> Let's go there. Tanzel
asking about being a glutton.
And when you get there, brother 23, read
that verse
20 to 21.
>> 21. Yes.
>> All right. and we're going to open it up
to the panel.
>> Be not among vine bidders, among riotous
eaters of flesh. For the drunker and the
glutton shall come to profit, and the
drowsiness shall clothe a man with rags.
>> All right. So, well, um, one of the
places we can go, let's go to Matthews,
uh, 11. Matthews 11 and we're gonna open
it up to the panel and let's see
what they said about Jesus here.
Matthew 11 and 19.
Let's see what they said about Jesus
here. Because sometimes when you call a
man glutton or wine bibble might be in
the eyes of youth. That's how you see it
that way. Go ahead read.
The son of man came eating and drinking.
They said, "Behold, a man gluttonous and
a wine bibber, a friend of publicans and
sinners, but wisdom is justified of her
children."
>> That's one place. Anyone else?
>> Well, the whole thing go back to what
the book say.
>> Oh, no. The commandments, thou shalt not
eat too much. Right.
>> Right.
>> No, it ain't no sin.
>> Nope.
>> Yep. And um cuz you mentioned that. I
know Tanzel might or might not be there,
but we'll read it again at 1 John 3 and
4. And this is what it say.
>> Go ahead, Tanzel.
Whosoever committh sin, transgress also
the law, for sin is the transgression of
the law.
>> All right, so we're going to leave it
right there as we continue to move on.
Next question. Skyrider asks, "What is
Amos 5
23 and 24 referring to exactly?"
>> Amos 5:23 and 24.
>> Yes.
>> Let's go there. Tanzel, Hosea, Joel,
then we got Amos.
>> Amos 5.
>> Amos 5
>> 23
>> and 24. And then we're gonna open up to
the panel. They want some light shed on
that question. Go right ahead, brother.
>> Take thou away from me the noise of thy
songs, for I will not hear the melody of
thy vows, but let judgment run down as
waters and righteousness as a mighty
stream.
>> We know 24 is explanatory,
self-explanatory.
When you're serving God, find out what
right is. and let your your
righteousness run down as mighty waters
and as a mighty stream.
>> 23 is talking about how, you know, they
they got the songs, they playing the
music. He said, "I'm not going to hear
the melody of your vials or your songs."
He said, "But judgment run down and
righteousness as a mighty stream, right?
>> Because this is what the people
>> must do. We It's about living righteous.
It ain't about a party or, you know, a
concert or something like that. But, you
know,
>> right,
>> even if you singing so-called religious
songs like they do all the time on the
Sunday churches, but then they breaking
the law.
>> Yes.
>> All that simple. I mean, yeah, at the
beginning of the of the session,
>> you know, uh right your your son, your
your son, the thing that you do that you
appain to me, he said, I ain't got
nothing to do with that.
>> You know, you talking about you going up
yana and the Bible teaches you thy
kingdom come.
>> Hey,
read that verse 18 right there. Read
what it say because this is what he
talking about. But the people don't talk
about this part. Go ahead. Mhm.
[clears throat]
>> Woe unto you that desire the day of the
Lord, but to what end is it for you, the
day of the Lord is darkness and not
light.
>> Mhm. So, it's going to be a time of
drama, but they ain't talking about that
drama.
>> They, you know, they they praise dancing
and speaking in tongues and all kind of
other stuff. So,
>> Yep. That's right, Dre. And and if you
like you said with the songs, you know
why you singing and you doing verse 26?
Read 26 too. Tanzel,
>> but you have borne the tabernacle of
your Molech and Shyan, your image, the
star of your God, which you made to
yourselves.
>> So he told us he a jealous God. You
going to make your own God, saying,
"Hey, what you singing up for and you
doing all these things that's against
God?" Hey Cornell, can we can we read um
Ezekiel 33
verse 31 and 32?
>> Ezekiel 33.
>> Mhm.
>> Go ahead. Tel 33.
>> Go ahead.
>> 33.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Verse 3132.
And they come unto thee as the people
cometh, and they sit before thee as my
people, and they hear thy words, but
they will not do them. For with their
mouth they show much love, but their
heart goes after their covetousness. And
lo, thou are unto them as a very lovely
song, of one that have a pleasant voice,
and can play well on an instrument, but
they hear thy words, but they do them
not. Mhm. Yep. Yeah. Good ad on there,
brother.
>> Like you said earlier, Dre, when you are
converted, then go and strengthen the
people,
>> right?
>> Yeah. Get away from that. Okay. We hope
that answered that question. Sister
Deborra, time check for the next one.
>> Uh, yes. The time is 8:49.
Zion says, "I see videos about kids
waking up in the hospital and say they
saw Jesus. Is it possible that they did?
>> Let's open that up to the panel.
>> You can't dispute it. Anything is
possible.
>> Mhm.
Yep. So there's your answer as we move
on.
>> Moving on. Be alert as can Gentiles hold
a leadership position anywhere in the
church?
Guess call.
>> Well, go back
and read what the Lord said
uh when he bring him in the land. He
said, "Don't put no king over you."
You know, so Gentiles can do anything
but teach. But as far as leadership is
concerned, then they have to be done by
Israel. remember you had a mixed
multitude that come out of of Egypt and
they don't speak of no Gentiles in a
leadership
role. Then you had the [clears throat]
uh
Jesus picked 12 apostles.
He didn't pick one gentile
in there to go out and deal with. In
fact, when a gentile want to know
something, he sent which is he sent him
to Peter. So he can serve but not as a
leader.
>> Mhm. Yep. And that's not a racist thing.
It is written that way.
>> Written is the way it is.
>> That's the way it is.
Okay. We're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Yes. Next question. Sky uh Sky Rider
asks, "Can someone elaborate more on
Proverb 24 verse 16?"
>> All right.
>> What is What is fall into mischief?
>> All right. Proverbs 24.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
Let's read that, brother. We talking
about a just man when he fall.
>> For a just man fallth seven times and
rises up again.
>> That's right.
>> For the wicked shall fall into mischief.
>> Yep. So, wicked can fall into mischief
and not get up. Just keep doing wicked.
Well, see, well, that's the whole thing
is if you just you fall, but you don't
do it on purpose. But the wicked
>> uh uh uh
is is about mischief.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That's right. You know, they they they
make it sound cute talking, oh, he's so
mischievous. No, he's a sinner. That's
what mischief is. Is somebody that
breaks the law.
But if you just if you just you can sin
and uh uh uh and and and you can recover
from it. But it's always been like that.
Let's go into the fourth chapter and
look at it what I'm talking about.
Leviticus 4 and start reading at verse
one.
The Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
speaking to the children of Israel,
saying, If a soul shall sin through
ignorance against any of the
commandments of the Lord concerning
things,
>> he said, "If they should sin in
ignorance," didn't they?
>> That's right.
>> Then uh uh you can come to the priest.
But well, just read just read that whole
verse. So, I want you to look at uh uh
go ahead and finish it.
>> Speak to the children of Israel, saying,
"If a soul shall sin through ignorance
against any of the commandments of the
Lord, concerning things which ought not
to be done, and shall do against any of
them.
If the priest that is anointed do sin
according to the sin of the people, then
let him bring forth his sin which he
have seen a young bullock without
blemish unto the Lord for a sin
offering.
>> Go ahead.
>> And he shall bring the bullock unto the
door of the tabernacle of the
congregation before the Lord, and shall
lay his hand upon the bullock's head,
and kill the bullocks before the Lord.
And the priest that is anointed shall
take of the bullock's blood and bring it
to the tabernacle of the congregation.
And the priest shall dip his finger in
the blood and sprinkle of the blood
seven times before the Lord before the
veil of the sanctuary.
>> Okay? And then and then the Lord will
then he can make an atonement for it.
But this is in ignorance. Skip down to
verse 13. And if the whole congregation
of Israel, saying through ignorance, and
the thing be hid from the eyes of the
assembly, they have done somewhat
against any of the commandments of the
Lord, concerning things which should not
be done, and are guilty.
For the sin which they have sinned
against it is known, then the
congregation shall offer a young bullock
for the sin, and bring him before the
tabernacle of the congregation.
And and then and the priest going to
take the take the blood of the bullock
and sprinkle it. Read verse 20.
>> And he shall do with the bullock as he
did with the bullock for a sin offering.
So shall he
>> so shall he do with this. And the priest
shall make an atonement for them and it
shall be forgiven them.
So now that's so when you're sin you
fail but few of the people but righteous
they fail uh uh not intending to do it.
>> That's why I say if you fall seven time
you can get up. But the wicked uh uh he
going to fall in the mischief. Let me
show you what I'm talking about. Now
let's go into Hebrews the 10th chapter.
Hebrews chapter 10 and uh we're going to
start reading around verse 26.
We going to read 26 and 27.
>> Well, if we sin willfully
after that we have receive.
>> There you go. If we sin willfully now
that's not in ignorance, is it? Go
ahead, finish that.
>> After that we have received the
knowledge of the truth, there remainth
no more sacrifice for sins, but a
certain fearful looking forth judgment
and fiery indignation which shall devour
the adversaries.
>> So the difference is righteous man falls
seven times. That mean he not intended
to sin but he end up doing it. When he
find it, he repent. He ain't got to do
no sacrifice now because Jesus have
already died.
But
>> he's going to fall in mischief. What
makes him wicked? Because he is sin and
willfully. So the only thing he have to
look for is the lake of fire. So he
going to fall into more mischief. That's
all I got to say.
>> That's why that 12 that Daniel 12:10
said, "The wicked shall do wickedly."
>> Yeah. [clears throat]
Yeah. That's for sure. And hey, please
cut it out because it is a fearful thing
to fall into the hands of the living
God.
>> Absolutely.
>> All right.
>> We hope that that answered your question
there, Sister Deborah. You know that
time be flying when you're having fun.
Time checking. Next question, please.
>> Yes. Uh, this will be the last question.
The time is 8:57.
Zion says,
"I'm the only one in my family that has
been baptized in Jesus' name. Keep the
Sabbath. Don't eat unclean foods, etc. I
I'm also the only one that is having it
the hardest. What am I doing wrong?"
>> It might be doing everything right, but
hooray for you. All the things you just
said you doing. Hey, that's on the
program of God. But open to the panel.
What is it that she is doing wrong other
than letting her light shine?
>> Hey, where's that written jay? Paul told
you through much tribulation, we must
enter into the kingdom of God,
>> right?
>> You going to suffer for him, sisters and
brothers. Nobody gets a free ride.
Nobody.
>> So, you doing the right thing. And
Matthew the 5th chapter told you let's
go to that Matthew tanzel Matthew 5
>> and that passage is in uh Acts 14 and 22
Jew.
>> So my brother uh when you get into them
kind of emotions or stuff like that read
Matthew the 5th chapter. Boy is it
encouraging. Is it encouraging Matthew
5 and pick it up at verse uh 11. Start
at verse 10.
Blessed are they which are persecuted
for righteousness sake.
>> Yes, for
>> theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
>> For righteousness say you serving the
true living God. Go ahead.
>> Blessed are ye when men shall revile you
and persecute you and shall say all
manner of evil against you falsely for
my sake.
>> Why? Continue. rejoicing and be
exceeding glad for great your reward in
heaven.
For so persecute they the prophets
prophets which were before you.
>> So sisters and brothers when you suffer
for righteousness sake and you saying
you trying to serve the true and living
God that is a blessing instead of crying
or uh and we all go through it but in
lift yourself up and thank God because
you're on the right track. You are on
the right track. So therefore, you like
the book said, verse 14, you the salt of
the earth. So you walk in righteousness
and let your family see you. Who knows
if they will see you and repent because
you got answers and they don't. So when
the time comes, you you can answer them.
>> Go read scriptures. We we going to get
out of the advice. We going to read a
couple of scriptures. Go and show where
Jesus said what he brought. He said,
"Bring not what." I want somebody to
read find it and read.
>> That's Matthew 10. That's where I wanted
to go. Matthew 10
>> and verse uh 34. Matthew 10 and 34.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you, guest caller.
>> Think not that I am come to send peace
on earth. I came not to send peace, but
a sword.
For I am come to set a man at variance
against his father, and his daughter
against her mother, and the
daughter-in-law against her
mother-in-law.
And a man's f shall be they of his own
household.
But he that love ath father or mother
more than me is not worthy of me. And he
that love a son or daughter more than me
is not worthy of me. And he that taketh
not his cross and follow after me is not
worthy of me.
>> For he that findeth his life shall lose
it. And he that loseth his life for my
sake shall find it.
>> There you go.
>> One other place find out where the Lord
is going to let you know that sometime
your drummer is not coming from inside
the house. It coming from outside the
house. let you know what the Lord so
warned you about this where the Lord
said put on the whole armor of God.
Somebody go read
>> Ephesians 6.
>> Yeah.
>> Ephesians 6th chapter 10.
>> Fixing what?
>> Um we can uh
>> verse 10.
>> Uh 10. Start at 10.
Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Yeah. Put on the whole armor of God.
Yeah. Verse uh read 10 and 11. Go ahead.
We read down some more. Go ahead. Tia.
>> Finally, brethren, be strong in the Lord
and in the power of his might.
>> Put on the whole armor of God that ye
may be able to stand against the ws of
the devil. But we wrestle not against
flesh and blood, but against
principalities,
against powers, against the rulers of
the doctrines of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places.
>> One more verse.
>> Now you now this this put it on the
spiritual level. That means Satan is
>> have people fumbling with you like on
your job. Sometimes sometime you just
have a hard time just like the Lord let
Satan do to Job, right? He said, "We're
dealing with spiritual wickedness in
high places." But keep reading.
>> Wherefore take unto you the whole armor
of God that he may be able to withstand
in the evil day, and having done all to
stand. So stand therefore, have your
loins girded about with truth, and
having on the breastplate of
righteousness.
You got to know what the truth is and
you got to live it. That's the breath of
rice. Let's go ahead and read.
>> And your feet sh with the preparation of
the gospel of peace above all taking the
shield of faith whereas ye shall be able
to quench all the fiery docks of the
wicked.
>> That mean
>> and take the helmet of salvation.
>> Listen that that shield of faith. Faith
is your shield. You got to bleed this
word of God. Yeah.
>> No matter what nobody come to you cuz
you dealing with spiritual wickedness in
high places. But finish that now.
>> And take the helmet of salvation and the
sword of the spirit which is
>> the word of God.
>> Helmet of salvation. The sword of the
spirit. That's the sword that Jesus say
he came cuz it's the word of God. So now
you ain't dealing but with only with
family members. You're dealing with
people on your job. You're dealing with
everyday stuff. Just remember,
>> that's right. Like the Lord said, "Hey,
be strong and of good courage. The Lord
will never leave you nor forsake you.
He'll be with you even until the end of
the world.
>> Reign always."
>> Walk in the word.
>> No matter what who say. That's all
right. Yep. All right, Sister Deborah.
Time check.
Okay, the t Okay, the time is 9:04.
>> All right, we have come to the end of
our program. We want to thank everybody
from all around the world who joined us
this evening. We enjoy taking part in
your questions and answering them. And
we say if you submitted a question, we
didn't get to it. Please don't resubmit
it. Sister Deborah will take it and put
it into rotation and we will deal with
that next Wednesday. So until we all
come together again, please be safe out
there, be blessed, stay prayed up, and
may the Lord have mercy on us all. As
brother Tanzel closes us out, our
Father, which are in heaven, hallowed be
thy name, thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread. And forgive
us of our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever. In Jesus name we
pray.